<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>

    <!-- Gene Category -->

    <GeneCategoryDef>
        <defName>BEWHSpaceMarine</defName>
        <label>space marine</label>
        <displayPriorityInXenotype>540</displayPriorityInXenotype>
    </GeneCategoryDef>

    <!-- Parent Gene -->

    <GeneDef Name="SpaceMarineParent" Abstract="True">
        <displayCategory>BEWHSpaceMarine</displayCategory>
        <marketValueFactor>1.05</marketValueFactor>
        <biostatCpx>2</biostatCpx>
        <canGenerateInGeneSet>false</canGenerateInGeneSet>
    </GeneDef>

    <GeneDef Name="PrimarisSpaceMarineParent" Abstract="True">
        <displayCategory>BEWHSpaceMarine</displayCategory>
        <marketValueFactor>1.25</marketValueFactor>
        <biostatCpx>3</biostatCpx>
        <biostatArc>1</biostatArc>
        <canGenerateInGeneSet>false</canGenerateInGeneSet>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Space Marine Genes-->

    <!-- Secondary Heart-->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_SecondaryHeart</defName>
        <label>secondary heart</label>
        <description>It is both the first and the easiest of the gene-seed that is implanted on a
            neophyte, allowing not only to survive the loss of his original heart but to exceed its
            performance in combat, and survive low oxygen environments in case of a hull breach.
            While it occupies little space in the chest cavity (because the neophyte at this point
            is not a hulking mass) it is still a very efficient organ compared to its baseline
            counterpart, its design almost a work of art by the Emperor. The first prototype of the
            secondary heart was used in the Proto-Legionaires primordial strain and it was one of
            the few organs that were already stable, its simplicity combined with its performance
            make the secondary heart a drastical boost without much of a risk, if at all, such is
            its low risk of implantation that it is usually implanted with the ossmodula and the
            biscopea at the same time.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/SecondaryHeartIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>1</displayOrderInCategory>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>BloodPumping</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.25</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>Can survive loss of heart</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <minAgeActive>14</minAgeActive>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Kind</def>
            </li>
            <li>
                <def>SpeedOffset</def>
                <degree>-1</degree>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM1</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Ossmodula -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Ossmodula</defName>
        <label>ossmodula</label>
        <description>The ossmodula is a small gland located between the hypophysis and the
            hypothalamus, both of which are the main regulator of the human hormones, from gonades
            to growth.. It is by a chain of negative and positive feedbacks that the hypothalamus
            control the hypophysis and its hormonal synthesis and that's where the ossmodula comes
            in. As a man-in-the-middle organ, the ossmodula modifies the input and output of the
            hypothalamus and boosts the synthesis capabilities of the hypophysis, while also
            creating its own kind of growth hormone that supercedes the normal HGH and gives the
            astartes their iconic size and durability... As its name implies, Oss (from ossium,
            bone) and modula (from modulatus, to regulate), it regulates bone growth and coupled
            with a specific diet it gives the neophyte, after a couple years, a very dense skeletal
            system with ceramite infused in it, plus a bullet-proof fused ribcage that coupled with
            the biscopea, will be surrounded by stronger muscle.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/OssmodulaIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>2</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_SecondaryHeart</prerequisite>
        <bodyType>Hulk</bodyType>
        <sterilize>true</sterilize>
        <statOffsets>
            <ArmorRating_Blunt>0.15</ArmorRating_Blunt>
            <ArmorRating_Sharp>0.15</ArmorRating_Sharp>
            <ArmorRating_Heat>0.05</ArmorRating_Heat>
        </statOffsets>
        <statFactors>
            <Fertility>0</Fertility>
            <LeatherAmount>1.25</LeatherAmount>
            <MeatAmount>1.25</MeatAmount>
            <Mass>1.25</Mass>
        </statFactors>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Delicate</def>
            </li>
            <li>
                <def>Wimp</def>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <bodyScaleFactor>(1.15, 1.15)</bodyScaleFactor>
                <headScaleFactor>(1.15, 1.15)</headScaleFactor>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <minAgeActive>12</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM2</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Biscopea -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Biscopea</defName>
        <label>biscopea</label>
        <description>The biscopea is the last organ to be introduced alongside the secondary heart
            and there is good reason for that, while the secondary heart allows the nutrition of a
            bigger mass and the ossmodula improves the neophytes basic structure, the biscopea
            builds upon them with a stronger muscle layer. Working similarly to the ossmodula, as in
            hormonally, the biscopea allows the muscle of the neophyte to grow alongside the bones,
            not only in size but also in durability, with stronger fibers that are predisposed to
            high strain without requiring the physical training that a normal human would. These
            muscles are not only stronger and efficient but also able to regenerate faster, helping
            with fatigue in long campaigns.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/BiscopeaIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>3</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Ossmodula</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <CarryingCapacity>80</CarryingCapacity>
        </statOffsets>
        <statFactors>
            <MeleeDamageFactor>1.6</MeleeDamageFactor>
            <StaggerDurationFactor>0.5</StaggerDurationFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Manipulation</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.2</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <aptitudes>
            <Melee>5</Melee>
        </aptitudes>
        <passionMod>
            <skill>Melee</skill>
            <modType>AddOneLevel</modType>
        </passionMod>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>No loss in melee skill</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <caravanCarryingFactor>1.3</caravanCarryingFactor>
                <noSkillLoss>Melee</noSkillLoss>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <minAgeActive>12</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM3</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Haemastamen -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Haemastamen</defName>
        <label>haemastamen</label>
        <description>Hemoglobin is the molecule used by humans to carry oxygen and carbon dioxide, a
            complex protein with four groups called Heme that use iron to bond to O2 and CO2 and
            transport it. The Haemastamen is an organ inserted right into a main blood vessel that
            acts as a filter to the Eritrocites that the neophyte produces, and modifies them to
            have a better version of hemoglobin, which causes superior O2 carrying capacity and
            brigher red blood due to it. It also changes the affinity so that the heme groups won't
            get polluted with carbon monoxide and similar. The improved affinity for O2 allows for
            more nutrition while the affinity for CO2 allows in its elimination, and so disrupts the
            acidification of blood and fatigue so that the neophyte can not only work harder, but
            longer.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/HaemastamenIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>4</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Biscopea</prerequisite>
        <statFactors>
            <MoveSpeed>1.25</MoveSpeed>
        </statFactors>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>BloodPumping</capacity>
                <offset>0.4</offset>
            </li>
            <li>
                <capacity>BloodPumping</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.2</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Industriousness</def>
                <degree>-1</degree>
            </li>
            <li>
                <def>Industriousness</def>
                <degree>-2</degree>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <minAgeActive>14</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM4</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Larraman's Organ  -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_LarramansOrgan</defName>
        <label>larraman's organ</label>
        <description>An organ designed to secrete a special kind of byo-engineered cells, the
            Larraman's cells. These cells are an upgrade on normal human platelets, able to locate
            and fix damage to blood vessels. These cells use leucocytes as their main transport to
            arrive to damaged areas where they deploy and fix any tearing using themselves as a
            barrier, the main difference with platelets is that they are able to aggregate in a way
            that allows them to "patch-up" astartes vessels, which are bigger and stronger, but also
            to directly form clots and stop blood flow into fully opened blood vessels.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/LarramansOrganIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>5</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Haemastamen</prerequisite>
        <geneClass>Gene_Clotting</geneClass>
        <statFactors>
            <InjuryHealingFactor>4</InjuryHealingFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>Bleeding wounds close very quickly.</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <minAgeActive>13</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM5</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Catalepsean Node -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_CatalepseanNode</defName>
        <label>catalepsean node</label>
        <description>Installed in the brain stem, the Catalepsean node periodically tests for stress
            hormones and is able to detect a forceful lack of sleep in the neophyte, then, using its
            nervous connections as a node, it cuts off certain parts of the brain so that sleep is
            simulated to allow for longer wake periods. While dangerous to use for prolongued
            periods, it allows the neophyte to stay alert during an extended siege or defense and
            was instrumental in the defense of Terra in the Horus invasion. Its one of the reasons
            why astartes can win fights against humans even while very outnumbered, they just don't
            care about a war of atrition. Once the catalepsean node is installed, there is a
            requirement to start hypno-therapy to "calibrate" it.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/CatalepseanNodeIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>6</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_LarramansOrgan</prerequisite>
        <abilities>
            <li>BEWH_CatalepseanNodeUnsleeping</li>
        </abilities>
        <descriptionHyperlinks>
            <AbilityDef>BEWH_CatalepseanNodeUnsleeping</AbilityDef>
        </descriptionHyperlinks>
        <statFactors>
            <RestFallRateFactor>0.9</RestFallRateFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Nerves</def>
                <degree>-1</degree>
            </li>
            <li>
                <def>Nerves</def>
                <degree>-2</degree>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <minAgeActive>17</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM6</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Preomnor -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Preomnor</defName>
        <label>preomnor</label>
        <description>The Preomnor pre, meaning before and Omnor from Omni, everything, is a small
            sack placed between the stomach and the esophagus, and as its name implies it allows to
            eat almost anything without consequences, even straight up poison that is isolated and
            stored in Betcher's glands. It works by a combination of specific and non-specific
            enzymes and tailored antigens to neutralize any danger that the ingested material poses
            to the neophyte. While often overlooked, the Preomnor is a miracle of imperial material
            science and one of the most complex organs.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/PreomnorIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>7</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_CatalepseanNode</prerequisite>
        <dontMindRawFood>true</dontMindRawFood>
        <foodPoisoningChanceFactor>0</foodPoisoningChanceFactor>
        <statFactors>
            <RawNutritionFactor>2</RawNutritionFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM7</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Omophagea -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Omophagea</defName>
        <label>omophagea</label>
        <description>The Omophagea is one of the least understood implants, seemingly allowing the
            neophyte to aquire the memories of animals, humans and xenos by eating them, Imperial
            consensus is that it works by the analysis of DNA, RNA or protein sequences that
            supposedly carry the memories of the deceased which are then transmitted directly to the
            brain, which is used in survival situations, a more sensible aproach would be that it
            doesn't access the actual memories of the eaten but it's genetic ones, analysis how
            certain creatures are genetically predisposed to some things, while the protein analysis
            could give light unto what it was doing just before dying, both by hormones and by cells
            present, or pathogens, the combination of this information could be used by the
            omophagea to speculate and then the brain of the neophyte translates that information in
            the form of a memory for understanding, as a complex analysis of chemical composition
            wouldn't be so useful.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/OmophageaIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>8</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Preomnor</prerequisite>
        <statFactors>
            <GlobalLearningFactor>1.25</GlobalLearningFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <abilities>
            <li>BEWH_OmophageaCorpseEat</li>
        </abilities>
        <descriptionHyperlinks>
            <AbilityDef>BEWH_OmophageaCorpseEat</AbilityDef>
        </descriptionHyperlinks>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM8</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Multi-lung -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_MultiLung</defName>
        <label>multi-lung</label>
        <description>The multi lung is but a bag, similar in composition to a lung but with similar
            enzymes and filters to the preomnor. Implanted just under the lungs to be able to fully
            use the diaphragm, the multi-lung is routed to a sphincter in the trachea so that it can
            be used alongside the other lungs to feed the now higher oxygen requirements due to the
            Haemastamen, but also so that it can close it, forcing all air input to come through it,
            in case the neophyte is in a dangerous atmosphere and the air needs to be filtered.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/Multi-LungIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>9</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Omophagea</prerequisite>
        <immuneToToxGasExposure>true</immuneToToxGasExposure>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>Tox gas immunity</li>
            <li>Can survive loss of lungs</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <statOffsets>
            <ToxicEnvironmentResistance>2</ToxicEnvironmentResistance>
        </statOffsets>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Breathing</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.3</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM9</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Occulobe -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Occulobe</defName>
        <label>occulobe</label>
        <description>The occulobe is implanted on the base of the frontal lobe, with a direct access
            to the occular nerves to which it's attached and connected directly, giving access to
            the retina inputs and functioning in two different ways: One is to modify the growth of
            the eye with hormonal therapy, giving the neophyte better sight and more compact,
            efficient retinal cells. The other is to allow the optical input to be directly
            transmitted and translated in the brain for optical hypno-therapy.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/OcculobeIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>10</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_MultiLung</prerequisite>
        <ignoreDarkness>true</ignoreDarkness>
        <statFactors>
            <AimingDelayFactor>0.85</AimingDelayFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Sight</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.4</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <aptitudes>
            <Shooting>5</Shooting>
        </aptitudes>
        <passionMod>
            <skill>Shooting</skill>
            <modType>AddOneLevel</modType>
        </passionMod>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>No loss in shooting skill</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <noSkillLoss>Shooting</noSkillLoss>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM10</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Lyman's Ear -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_LymansEar</defName>
        <label>lyman's ear</label>
        <description>The Lyman's ear is an inner ear implant that allows the carrier to modify their
            sound perception by applying digital filters, for example doing frequency sweeps and
            looking for known patterns. This is used by some chapters for secret codes in
            frequencies that only they can hear and know to look for. As the implant sits in the
            inner ear, is also has mechanical control of the complex bone structure that is used for
            balance, and is interfered with so that the neophyte can not only be immune to motion
            sickes but also be able to work flawlessly on low or even zero gravity environments. The
            Lyman's ear in particular is one of the most mechanically complex implants and one of
            the few that have a digital component, it is good then that only one is implanted on the
            neophyte, as an electronic attack could render them deaf if they didnt still have a
            normal, fully organic ear.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/LymansEarIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>11</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Occulobe</prerequisite>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Hearing</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.6</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <aptitudes>
            <Social>2</Social>
        </aptitudes>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>No loss in social skill</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <noSkillLoss>Social</noSkillLoss>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM11</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Sus-an Membrane -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_SusAnMembrane</defName>
        <label>sus-an membrane</label>
        <description>Carriers possess an organ within the their cranium, this organ eventually
            produces a membrane comprised of genetically-engineered neural tissue that merges with
            the recipient's cerebrum, that allows them to enter a state of suspended animation, the
            organ will shut down all biological and psychic functions</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/Sus-anMembraneIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>12</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_LymansEar</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <MentalBreakThreshold>-0.3</MentalBreakThreshold>
        </statOffsets>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <abilities>
            <li>BEWH_Sus_anMembraneStasis</li>
        </abilities>
        <descriptionHyperlinks>
            <AbilityDef>BEWH_Sus_anMembraneStasis</AbilityDef>
        </descriptionHyperlinks>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM12</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Melanochrome -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Melanochrome</defName>
        <label>melanochrome</label>
        <description>The Melanochrome, melano from melanin, a substance used as protection against
            the sun, and chrome from color, is another hormonal secretor that uses the lynphatic
            system as transport for its hormones. Designed to improve the radiation protection of
            the neophyte by assisting in the creation of more or less melanin (For example, giving
            the sons of Vulcan their black color and the angels their pale skin, both of which are
            mutations of the melanochrome) in case of high radiation exposure but also it is
            designed to capture certain metals from the diet and use them in the formation of skin
            cells to protect against other types of radiation, these metals are usually ingested
            through their Astartes specific meals and are comprised of heavy metals like lead and
            gold, taking particular care in not using ferro-magnetic ones.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/MelanochromeIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>13</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_SusAnMembrane</prerequisite>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM13</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Oolitic Kidney -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_OoliticKidney</defName>
        <label>oolitic kidney</label>
        <description>The Oolitic kidney, while called a kidney is not really designed to work
            alongside its normal kidneys, but as an emergency measure. It does however have the same
            function of filtering but on a degree that even machines are not able to get close to.
            The oolitic filter works as a sort of strengthened dialysis in case either the preomnor
            or multi-lung have failed in their detoxification. As a last line of defense against
            toxins and poisons, the Oolitic kidney will do everything it can to rid the neophyte
            from the dangerous substance and for that it puts him into a sort of coma, to lower
            metabolic rate as much as possible and prevent further system exposure to the dangerous
            material while it is slowly and meticulously filtered out. When not necessary for
            emergency detox, it is used as regulatory for other implants.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/OoliticKidneyIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>14</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Melanochrome</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <ToxicResistance>0.75</ToxicResistance>
        </statOffsets>
        <statFactors>
            <ImmunityGainSpeed>1.4</ImmunityGainSpeed>
        </statFactors>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>BloodFiltration</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.2</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <biostatMet>3</biostatMet>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Immunity</def>
                <degree>-1</degree>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM14</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Neuroglottis -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Neuroglottis</defName>
        <label>neuroglottis</label>
        <description>The Neuroglotis is a sensor implanted on the mouth cavity, close to the
            nasopharyn and connected to the nasal cavity. Its main function is sensing the chemical
            composition of liquids, gasses and solids that pass through either the nose or mouth and
            sending very specific nervous signals to the neophyte, allowing the instant verification
            of toxicity and nutritional value, but also the capacity of smelling and recognizing
            substances that humans usually don't, for example, hormones. While it can't be denied
            that is very useful in survival situations, it is often overlooked how useful it is in
            social interactions, in which the neophyte could recognize stress and other factors just
            by smelling or in case of a surprise attack down-wind, the alert could prove a decisive
            factor in victory.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/NeuroglottisIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>15</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_OoliticKidney</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <ToxicResistance>0.75</ToxicResistance>
        </statOffsets>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Eating</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.4</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM15</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Mucranoid -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Mucranoid</defName>
        <label>mucranoid</label>
        <description>The Mucranoid is a long organ installed alongside the spine and connected to
            the lynphatic system for transport, it detects a chemical stimuli that is usually
            self-administered in case of emergency and then secretes signals that travel to the skin
            and close up the pores using a waxy mucus, as more of it is released the entire skin
            ends up covered and then a neural signal is sent to the brain to enter a deep-coma,
            reducing metabolism to almost nothing. While protected this way, the neophyte is immune
            to the vacuum and coldness of space, keeping them alive until he can be rescued. Of
            course, this can also be used in other circumstances in which he has received mortal
            wounds, the mucranoid and the larraman's cells work together to put him into the best
            position possible to wait for rescue.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/MucranoidIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>16</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Neuroglottis</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <ComfyTemperatureMin>-60</ComfyTemperatureMin>
            <ComfyTemperatureMax>60</ComfyTemperatureMax>
        </statOffsets>
        <minAgeActive>16</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM16</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Betcher's Gland -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_BetchersGland</defName>
        <label>betcher's gland</label>
        <description>The Betcher's gland is copmrised of 2 glands that work in tandem, implanted on
            different parts of the mouth depending on preference, they are able to turn saliva into
            a corrosive acid using similar processes to the stomach glands, but with stronger acids
            ingested through the Astartes specific diet and stored after being processed by the
            preomnor. This saliva is strong enough to melt steel or even be used in combat, blinding
            or even killing an enemy by spitting in his head, but it is usually used as a last
            resort as it also hurts the mouth of the neophyte and the healing takes quite a while,
            sometimes even rendering them mute. The most used case is to digest harshers substances
            in survival situations, the betcher's gland can output its acid back into the preomnor
            to help digestion of things like cellulose from grass or bark for emergency
            carbohydrates. Some chapters forgo this function and instead use them to store
            specifically tailored poisons to which they are completely immune and drink in their
            diet, so that it can be later used either in combat or in capture situations.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/BetchersGlandIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>17</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Mucranoid</prerequisite>
        <abilities>
            <li>BEWH_BetchersSpit</li>
        </abilities>
        <capMods>
            <li>
                <capacity>Talking</capacity>
                <postFactor>1.15</postFactor>
            </li>
        </capMods>
        <descriptionHyperlinks>
            <AbilityDef>BEWH_BetchersSpit</AbilityDef>
        </descriptionHyperlinks>
        <minAgeActive>17</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM17</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Progenoid Glands -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_ProgenoidGlands</defName>
        <label>progenoid glands</label>
        <description>The progenoid glands are installed in the neck and in the chest and are by far
            the most complex of them all, a biological precision machine that detects other
            gene-seed implants and copies their DNA into seeds that can then be extracted and via
            proper care by an apothecary, gestated into any of the gene-seed organs. Due to the
            nature of this reproduction, very similar to cloning, there is an inherent risk of
            mutation which is then passed down to future neophytes and so, much care is taken in the
            purification and analysis of the results and sometimes much of it is discarded when
            chapters are bound to the warp for long periods. This is the reason why chapters with
            very radioactive worlds tend to have more mutations and a lax attitude towards them.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/ProgenoidsIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>18</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_BetchersGland</prerequisite>
        <makeImmuneTo>
            <li>Flu</li>
            <li>Malaria</li>
            <li>SleepingSickness</li>
            <li>Plague</li>
            <li>WoundInfection</li>
            <li>LungRot</li>
            <li>GutWorms</li>
            <li>MuscleParasites</li>
            <li>LungRotExposure</li>
        </makeImmuneTo>
        <hediffGiversCannotGive>
            <li>Carcinoma</li>
            <li>HeartAttack</li>
            <li>BadBack</li>
            <li>Frail</li>
            <li>Cataract</li>
            <li>Dementia</li>
            <li>Alzheimers</li>
            <li>Asthma</li>
            <li>HeartArteryBlockage</li>
            <li>Cirrhosis</li>
            <li>DrugOverdose</li>
        </hediffGiversCannotGive>
        <biologicalAgeTickFactorFromAgeCurve>
            <points>
                <li>(21, 0)</li>
            </points>
        </biologicalAgeTickFactorFromAgeCurve>
        <customEffectDescriptions>
            <li>Allows you to harvest these progenoids glands once after 60 days, allowing you to
                create anothe space marine</li>
        </customEffectDescriptions>
        <minAgeActive>18</minAgeActive>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <hediffToWholeBody>BEWH_ProgenoidGlandsGrowth</hediffToWholeBody>
                <diseaseProgressionFactor>0.35</diseaseProgressionFactor>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM18</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Black Carapace -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="SpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_BlackCarapace</defName>
        <label>black carapace</label>
        <description>The black carapace is the last organ to be implanted, a combination of
            biological and mechanical technology that surpasses most of the implants and is the last
            step before a neophyte can finally be called an Astartes, in honor of its creator, Amar
            Astarte. Its design complex but at the same time beautifully simple in its delivery,
            based on biological fibrous tissue implanted under the skin, which then grows not unlike
            a cancer throughout the body with invasive and painful fibers that connect themselves to
            the nervous system. This process lasts for a couple hours and is said to be one of the
            most painful experiences a neophyte has. Once the Astartes has finally emerged from its
            arduous final implantation, he is then cut into by an Apothecary to install connection
            ports to then be used to interact with the machine spirit of their power armor and reach
            for its full potential, a neurolink between man and machine so that they both can feel
            and act synchronously.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/BlackCarapaceIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>19</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_ProgenoidGlands</prerequisite>
        <statFactors>
            <IncomingDamageFactor>0.90</IncomingDamageFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <painFactor>0.75</painFactor>
        <minAgeActive>19</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>SM19</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Primaris Genes-->

    <!-- Sinew Coil -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="PrimarisSpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_SinewCoil</defName>
        <label>sinew coil</label>
        <description>Carriers sinews are reinforced with durametallic coil-cables that can contract
            with incredible force, magnifying his strength as well as giving his body another layer
            of defence.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/SinewCoilIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>21</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Biscopea</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <CarryingCapacity>100</CarryingCapacity>
        </statOffsets>
        <statFactors>
            <MeleeDamageFactor>1.3</MeleeDamageFactor>
            <IncomingDamageFactor>0.85</IncomingDamageFactor>
            <StaggerDurationFactor>0</StaggerDurationFactor>
        </statFactors>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <caravanCarryingFactor>2</caravanCarryingFactor>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <suppressedTraits>
            <li>
                <def>Beauty</def>
                <degree>-1</degree>
            </li>
            <li>
                <def>Beauty</def>
                <degree>-2</degree>
            </li>
        </suppressedTraits>
        <minAgeActive>13</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>PM1</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Magnificat -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="PrimarisSpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_Magnificat</defName>
        <label>magnificat</label>
        <description>Carriers possess a small, thumbnail-sized lobe in the brain's cortex that make
            them physically even larger, stronger and with faster reaction times than his
            non-Primaris brethren.</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/MagnificatIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>22</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Biscopea</prerequisite>
        <statOffsets>
            <MeleeDodgeChance>10</MeleeDodgeChance>
        </statOffsets>
        <statFactors>
            <AimingDelayFactor>0.85</AimingDelayFactor>
            <MeleeWeapon_CooldownMultiplier>0.85</MeleeWeapon_CooldownMultiplier>
            <RangedCooldownFactor>0.85</RangedCooldownFactor>
            <MeleeHitChance>1.2</MeleeHitChance>
            <LeatherAmount>1.15</LeatherAmount>
            <MeatAmount>1.15</MeatAmount>
            <Mass>1.15</Mass>
        </statFactors>
        <modExtensions>
            <li Class="VanillaGenesExpanded.GeneExtension">
                <bodyScaleFactor>(1.05, 1.05)</bodyScaleFactor>
                <headScaleFactor>(1.05, 1.05)</headScaleFactor>
            </li>
        </modExtensions>
        <minAgeActive>13</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>PM2</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

    <!-- Belisarian Furnace -->

    <GeneDef ParentName="PrimarisSpaceMarineParent">
        <defName>BEWH_BelisarianFurnace</defName>
        <label>belisarian furnace</label>
        <description>Carriers possess a dormant organ that connects to both Astartes hearts. In
            times of extreme stress, or should the warrior's body undergo violent, damaging trauma,
            it expels great blurts of self-synthesized chemicals - a hyper-cocktail that simulates
            the biological action of combat stimms while also aiding in the rapid regrowth of
            tissue, bone and muscle</description>
        <iconPath>UI/Icons/Genes/BelisarianFurnaceIcon</iconPath>
        <displayOrderInCategory>23</displayOrderInCategory>
        <prerequisite>BEWH_Biscopea</prerequisite>
        <abilities>
            <li>BEWH_BelisarianFurnaceBoost</li>
        </abilities>
        <descriptionHyperlinks>
            <AbilityDef>BEWH_BelisarianFurnaceBoost</AbilityDef>
        </descriptionHyperlinks>
        <minAgeActive>13</minAgeActive>
        <exclusionTags>
            <li>PM3</li>
        </exclusionTags>
    </GeneDef>

</Defs>